### JD Martin

namtri@gmail.com ■ 303-513-7389 ■ LinkedIn ■ Golden, CO

### Summary

I am an analytical, creative software engineer with over 15 years of professional experience. I believe in making sure the project is done correctly and on time. Demonstrated ability learning new languages and codebases quickly, therefore able to make an immediate impact as a valued member of the team.

The company I'm looking for cares about their engineers and is interested in their long term growth. I'm a good fit for that type of environment because I understand technology is a constantly moving target, and knowing how and when a tool should be utilized can make all the difference to a successful project.

### **Core Technologies and Platforms**

PHP · HTML · CSS · JSON · XML · XSD · Javascript · ES5 · ES6 · React · NPM · Bootstrap · Linux · MySQL · Apache · Doctrine · OOP · SOA · AWS · GCP · SQL · C/C++ · GIT · Subversion · PVCS

# Work Experience

### Roswell Park Comprehensive Cancer Center, Remote

Data Conversion Specialist, September 2022 - August 2024

- Designed and Developed a process for converting Roswell Parks' patient records to a new platform using PHP.
- Used a chain of responsibility pattern with full data redundancy across the entire process to improve data tracking through the conversion.
- While reusability was important, considering the output of the four conversion files, the specific child class changes were properly encapsulated from the base functionality.
- With 6 months until launch we had a major change to appointment file requirements necessitating the refactor of the Appointment class, but overall changes were limited due to the flexibility of the code structure.
- Worked with the team to develop the documentation to ensure a smooth handoff of the code to the Roswell personnel.
- Participating in the mock and incremental launches lend my expertise to the full dataset.

### SitusAMC, Remote

Contractor, June 2021 - May 2022

- Working as a cross-platform teammate responsible for building proficiency in multiple applications to relieve project overflow.
- Converting the front-end Javascript application pages to a new home-grown system.
- Cross-training on a full stack application developed on the LAMP stack (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP).
- Designing and implementing rules in SQL as specified by the client.
- Work with testers, release managers, and owners on 3-week software release sprints.

### Teli Communications LLC, Centennial, CO

Senior Software Engineer, July 2018 - April 2021

Empowering businesses to connect with their customers with a suite of voice and messaging services. Providing powerful tools through both simple to use APIs and a portal interface for resellers and customers.

- Develop and maintain API and Portal environments using HTML/Javascript/PHP, jQuery, Fat Free Framework and AWS.
- As team lead, performed the research, design and development of a CRM module for the telecom

industry.

- Worked with the Romanian team to develop the front-end logic to build a message campaign registration system into Teli's portal.
- Designed and developed a dashboard to allow our sales team to track revenue targets.
- Integrate Teli's own callAPI functionality into CRM as click-2-call and SMS modals.
- Took ownership of Customer Support System and Local Number Portability enhancements.
- Develop and maintain procedural automated scripts.
- Mentored a junior software engineer, who works remotely in Romania, to develop a new ticket tracking system.

#### Connekt Inc., Denver, CO (Formerly: Delivery Agent)

Senior Software Engineer, May 2011 – February 2018

Build rich media contextual content on TVs and second screen devices for connecting consumers with leading brands and companies. Main responsibilities consist of both design and development for front and back-end applications on the Advanced Media Team.

- Successfully worked within a team of five developers to build a new modular application and Content Management System (CMS) using Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Python, ReactJS and Material-UI.
- Lead the design and development of building campaigns with comprehensive, full flow event tracking using Google Analytics and Rebrandly along with a custom tracking pixel to capture SMS clicks.
- Worked with a team to develop a next generation REST and Web Service API platform for iTV and third-party integration including Samsung, LG, Comcast, Sony and Roku platforms using PHP in a LAMP stack.
- Developed a series of modules, services, and libraries in a loosely coupled, highly cohesive manner to facilitate data transactions within the Delivery Agent engine or third-party APIs in PHP.
- Completed a multi-platform unification project with the expressed goal of merging Delivery Agent's PHP based Order Management System with Music Today's CMS.
- Integrating multiple third-party vendor SDKs, including Amazon Pay, Avalara, CDyne, Zend, and Doctrine.
- Extended in-house database object to support query builder functionality in PHP.
- A Facebook management module was integrated into the company's homegrown CMS.
- Collaboratively worked with the project team on several advertising campaigns for live and recorded television events, including the Superbowl and Survivor's 35th anniversary.
- Lead and delivered the final stage of a CES 2011 demo in partnership with Intel and Discovery.

#### **DISH Network**, Englewood, CO

Senior Analyst/Developer, August 2006 - January 2010

The main designer and developer for the Customer Service Application for the Set Top Box (STB). I worked as the server-side developer using: Java 5, WebLogic 10.3, XML, SVN, SOA, SQL, Maven.

- Developed server code to connect with 25 million STBs consisting of over 30 different models.
- Led the creation and maintenance of technical and interface documentation for the IT and Engineering groups.
- Participated in the development of a Base64 transformation application between Echostar and Google; all
  code was developed in a test driven development process with Junit and Cobertura for 100% code
  coverage.
- Successfully completed additional projects involving legacy applications which needed to be brought into a modern environment. My ability to read, understand and enhance other developers' code was essential to successfully deliver this goal.

## Ivy Bound, New Britain, CT

Developer/Administrator, February 2006 - August 2006

Designed and developed a website for a senatorial candidate in New York, using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and PHP.

- Wrote an email form using PHP and administered a dozen email accounts for campaign assistants.
- Performed image work performed in Adobe Photoshop 6.

### BenefitsXML Inc., Glastonbury, CT

Services Developer, August 2004 - August 2005

Developed a front-end demo portal, which connected to our web services benefits software. Tools included; J2EE, WebLogic, Apache, Jakarta Struts, PVCS, SQL, and XML.

- Transformed a Java Server Page portal to a new Struts based portal, with a focus on expandability through the use of Tiles.
- Extended Struts based Java classes to fit the needs of the benefits administration world.
- Flushed out bugs at an integrated build level before promotion to QA, which included using SQL to verify XML messaging from the Oracle database.
- Enhanced the unit regression test suite for our customers' user interface.

### Education

### Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science, June 2004

#### **Focused Curriculum**

- Artificial Intelligence (Al using LISP, Advanced Al using C++, Robot Building Lab using C)
- Human Computer Interaction (HCI, GUI using Java, Computer Graphics)
- Operating Systems (OS, Concurrent Programming using Java, Networks using C++)